<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome on William Blackerby: MLIS Portfolio</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on William Blackerby: MLIS Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. A High Level Metadata Workflow Overview</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-22-llc-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-22-llc-workflow/</guid><description>A High Level Metadata Workflow Overview # The semester is winding down and so is my time as a remote metadata intern for the Law Library of Congress. I ended up learning a ton about Unix text processing workhorses like aspell, awk, diff, find, grep, sed, and GNU Emacs as well as newer tools like Miller and Datasette. I incorporated these tools into several shell scripts to expedite my workflow, which is built around a python script I wrote to extract specific text from the PDF I was working with using regular expressions.</description></item><item><title>2. prep.sh and mlr</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-23-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-23-prep/</guid><description>prep.sh and mlr # I am an inexperienced shell scripter, but this project provided opportunities to do some productive work with the shell. My workflow starts with running prep.sh, a script that takes 2 or 3 arguments and is explained below.
Shebang # I&amp;rsquo;m on macOS, so my shebang line references zsh.
#! /usr/bin/env zsh Arguments # FILE=$(realpath $1) # full path to file name. must be pdf START=$2 # starting page of pdf file if [[ -n $3 ]] then FINISH=$3 # ending page of pdf file fi Here, I use realpath to take an argument like .</description></item><item><title>3. get_summaries.py</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-24-get-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-24-get-summaries/</guid><description>get_summaries.py # I hope to convert this file to ipynb format so interested folks can try the code out on their own. The code is currently published on GitHub.
Environment Setup # The Shebang Line # We add a shebang line in case we want to make this file executable.
#!/usr/bin/env python Necessary Libraries # Now we import the libraries we need.
import argparse import sys import re import csv from pathlib import Path from more_itertools import chunked from PyPDF2 import PdfReader The role of each library is explained below:</description></item><item><title>4. Emacs Workflow</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-25-emacs-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-25-emacs-workflow/</guid><description>Emacs Workflow # We&amp;rsquo;ve run prep.sh (and with it, get_summaries.py), so now we&amp;rsquo;ve got a directory full of text files to review. This is where GNU Emacs comes in.
Initially, I was doing all of this work on the command line, using iTerm2 on my Mac. I had a script that ran aspell on each text file before opening Neovim for each file for manual review. It worked fine, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very flexible, and to be honest, I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to become proficient in Emacs.</description></item><item><title>5. cleanup.sh</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-25-cleanup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-11-25-cleanup/</guid><description>cleanup.sh # With the text files edited, it&amp;rsquo;s time to clean up a little bit. That&amp;rsquo;s what cleanup.sh is for.
As usual, we start with the shebang line.
#!/usr/bin/env zsh We remove all of the no longer necessary backups. The -f makes sure there are no complaints in case no backups exist.
# remove temporary files rm -f *.bak rm -f *~ This section isn&amp;rsquo;t really necessary, but I added in to make working with one-off awk commands a little easier (tabs as delimiters are much easier to deal with than commas).</description></item><item><title>6. (meta)data(sette)</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-12-04-meta-data-sette/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/metadata/2022-12-04-meta-data-sette/</guid><description>(meta)data(sette) # Intro # After running cleanup.sh I like to make a local copy of it as a tab-separated file I can do various things with, including storing it in SQLite database with Datasette which, among other things, allows me to link the metadata with their associated text files.
The Code # As usual, it&amp;rsquo;s a shell script.
#!/usr/bin/env zsh I use wget to save the data to my local machine.</description></item><item><title>LS 501: Critical Cataloging: An LIS Hot Topic</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/practice/critcat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/practice/critcat/</guid><description>William Blackerby
Dr. Jeff Weddle
LS 501-925
6 October 2021
Critical Cataloging: An LIS Hot Topic
As part of their university libraries&amp;rsquo; commitment to equity, diversity, inclusion, and anti-racism, metadata specialists at the University of Washington published a statement on harmful language in catalog records and archival finding aids in August of 2021 (Casey et al., &amp;ldquo;Words Matter&amp;rdquo;). UW Libraries&amp;rsquo; publication of their &amp;ldquo;Critical Cataloging and Archival Description&amp;rdquo; statement takes place in the context of the ongoing, broader national conversation about equity, diversity, and inclusion prompted by systemic police violence and killings of unarmed Black people and brought to a head by the murder of George Floyd by Minneapolis police officer Derek Chauvin in May of 2020.</description></item><item><title>LS 501: Final Essays</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/finalessays501/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/finalessays501/</guid><description>William Blackerby
LS 501-925
Dr. Jeff Weddle
December 5, 2021
Final Essay Exam # Two Essential ALA Core Values # The two ALA core values that are most critical for the profession right now are Access and the Public Good. The amount of information available to our communities continues to grow and contribute to increasing both information overload and misinformation. Reputable information is often difficult to find or inaccessible due to paywalls, discoverability challenges, institutional and socio-cultural biases, and other impediments.</description></item><item><title>LS 501: Scholarly Communication Reading Response</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/rr501/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/rr501/</guid><description>William Blackerby
LS 501-925
Dr. Jeff Weddle
November 2, 2021
Scholarly Communication Reading Response
Prior to my engagement with the assigned readings on scholarly communication, besides knowing that peer review is important in the process, I had little idea of how scholarly journals are published. In fact, I was somewhat skeptical of why something that seemed as narrowly focused as academic publishing needed a week&amp;rsquo;s worth of our attention in this class.</description></item><item><title>LS 506: Ethical Cataloging Discussion Questions</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/practice/discussion-questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/practice/discussion-questions/</guid><description>Describe ethical concerns that occur in cataloging work. # In their exploration of what ethical cataloging is, Snow and Shoemaker (2020) note Intner's framing of cataloging ethics ``largely in terms of of institutional responsibilities: the library's ability or inability to meet its users' needs'' ( Citation: Snow&amp;#32;&amp;amp;&amp;#32;Shoemaker,&amp;#32;2020,&amp;#32;p.&amp;nbsp;535 Snow,&amp;#32; K.&amp;#32;&amp;amp;&amp;#32;Shoemaker,&amp;#32; B. &amp;#32; (2020). &amp;#32;Defining Cataloging Ethics: Practitioner Perspectives. Cataloging &amp;amp; Classification Quarterly,&amp;#32;58(6).&amp;#32;533–546. https://doi.org/10.1080/01639374.2020.1795767 ) . In other words, ethical cataloging is about how the library catalog affects the people who use it.</description></item><item><title>LS 506: Metadata Quality Discussion Questions</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/use/discussion-questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/use/discussion-questions/</guid><description>\usepackage{geometry}{=latex}
\geometry{margin=1in}{=latex}
\usepackage{setspace}{=latex}
\doublespacing{=latex}
#+cite_export: biblatex apa Discuss the different ways we can assess the quality of cataloging. # Any discussion of the quality of cataloging needs to begin with a definition of quality cataloging. Snow states that
In cataloging literature, &amp;ldquo;quality cataloging&amp;rdquo; has been defined in the following ways:
Accurate bibliographic information that meets users&amp;rsquo; needs and provides appropriate access in a timely fashion. What library users say it is.</description></item><item><title>LS 535: Case Study Memorandum</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/use/memo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/use/memo/</guid><description>+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+ | # Indian Springs School | +=======================================================================+ +&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+ First table has company name and second table has memo information
To: Tanya Yeager, Assistant Head of School for Finance and Administration
From: William Blackerby, Records Management Consultant
CC: Scott Schamberger, Head of School
Date: August 2, 2022
Re: Implementing a Records Retention Plan
: First table has company name and second table has memo information
As the National Association of Independent Schools Legal Advisory titled &amp;ldquo;Records Retention: What, How Long, and How?</description></item><item><title>LS 562: Digital Library Collection Development Policy Analysis and Services Description</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/notes/</guid><description>\usepackage{geometry}{=latex}
\geometry{margin=1in}{=latex}
\usepackage{setspace}{=latex}
\doublespacing{=latex}
#+cite_export: biblatex apa Introduction # According to their website,
The digital collection services of the Williams College Special Collections seeks to collect, manage, preserve and disseminate digital objects that support the educational mission of the College, are in need of preservation, are part of the history of the College, and are rare and unique. [@DigitalCollections, para. 1]
In this first part of this paper I will describe and analyze the Williams College Standards, Policies and Procedures for Digital Collections the using the framework presented in Xie and Matusiak's Discover Digital Libraries: Theory and Practice [@xieDiscoverDigitalLibraries2016b].</description></item><item><title>LS 566: Metadata Quality Problems</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/mqp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/mqp/</guid><description>William Blackerby
Dr. Steven MacCall
LS 566
25 September 2021
Assignment #2: Metadata quality problems
In their article &amp;ldquo;Achieving and Maintaining Metadata Quality: Toward a Sustainable Workflow for the IDEALS Institutional Repository,&amp;rdquo; Stein, Applegate, and Robbins give a useful overview of the kinds of metadata quality problems that can occur in collections before detailing how they developed a workflow to address metadata problems in the institutional repository they manage. Here I will summarize the kinds of problems they discuss.</description></item><item><title>Philosophy of LIS Practice</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/philosophy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/philosophy/</guid><description>A Reflective Essay on Information, Technology, Humanity, and Purpose # I distinctly remember what first piqued my interest in computing and technology. I was in sixth or seventh grade, spending the night at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house, and before settling in for a late night and early morning of action movie after action movie followed by far too little sleep, we sat at the desktop computer in the basement guestroom. Instead of playing through one of his favorite science fiction flight simulator games, my friend showed me how some text surrounded by angle brackets he typed out in NotePad could turn into a website anyone anywhere in the world could visit thanks to AngelFire.</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/resume/</guid><description>William T. Blackerby # 332 Willow Bend Road
Birmingham, AL 35209
205-240-3705
wmblackerby@gmail.com • LinkedIn • Github • Blog
Education # The University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, AL
Master of Library and Information Studies (online)
expected completion Spring 2023
Completed coursework: LS 500: Information Science and Technology, LS 501: Information and Communities, LS 535: Records Management, LS 566: Metadata and Semantic Web Fundamentals, LS 590: Linked Data, LS 506: Modern Cataloging and Classification, LS 562: Digital Libraries, LS 564: Programming for Digital Libraries, LS 570: Internship (Law Library of Congress Remote Metadata Internship) Coursework in progress Spring 2023: LS 513: Professional Paths, LS 569: Information Management, LS 570: Internship (Southern Music Research Center) The University of the South, Sewanee, TN</description></item><item><title>Visualizing Topics of 74th Congress Senate Bills and Joint Resolutions</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/2022-12-02-senate-topic-modeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/technology/2022-12-02-senate-topic-modeling/</guid><description>Visualizing Topics of 74th Congress Senate Bills and Joint Resolutions # This code is available to experiment with on Binder in a notebook with the filename tmr.ipynb. Be sure to check out the ner_mapping.ipynb notebook as well, in which I create a heatmap of states mentioned in Senate bills and joint resolutions during the 74th Congress.
In LS 562: Digital Libraries, we studied the application of machine learning tools to text analysis problems.</description></item></channel></rss>