<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Critically Articulating the Philosophy, Principles, and Ethics of Library and Information Science on William Blackerby: MLIS Portfolio</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/</link><description>Recent content in Critically Articulating the Philosophy, Principles, and Ethics of Library and Information Science on William Blackerby: MLIS Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LS 501: Final Essays</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/finalessays501/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/finalessays501/</guid><description>William Blackerby
LS 501-925
Dr. Jeff Weddle
December 5, 2021
Final Essay Exam # Two Essential ALA Core Values # The two ALA core values that are most critical for the profession right now are Access and the Public Good. The amount of information available to our communities continues to grow and contribute to increasing both information overload and misinformation. Reputable information is often difficult to find or inaccessible due to paywalls, discoverability challenges, institutional and socio-cultural biases, and other impediments.</description></item><item><title>LS 501: Scholarly Communication Reading Response</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/rr501/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/articulate/rr501/</guid><description>William Blackerby
LS 501-925
Dr. Jeff Weddle
November 2, 2021
Scholarly Communication Reading Response
Prior to my engagement with the assigned readings on scholarly communication, besides knowing that peer review is important in the process, I had little idea of how scholarly journals are published. In fact, I was somewhat skeptical of why something that seemed as narrowly focused as academic publishing needed a week&amp;rsquo;s worth of our attention in this class.</description></item></channel></rss>