<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Evaluating Technology-Mediated Access in Library and Information Services on William Blackerby: MLIS Portfolio</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/</link><description>Recent content in Evaluating Technology-Mediated Access in Library and Information Services on William Blackerby: MLIS Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LS 562: Digital Library Collection Development Policy Analysis and Services Description</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/notes/</guid><description>\usepackage{geometry}{=latex}
\geometry{margin=1in}{=latex}
\usepackage{setspace}{=latex}
\doublespacing{=latex}
#+cite_export: biblatex apa Introduction # According to their website,
The digital collection services of the Williams College Special Collections seeks to collect, manage, preserve and disseminate digital objects that support the educational mission of the College, are in need of preservation, are part of the history of the College, and are rare and unique. [@DigitalCollections, para. 1]
In this first part of this paper I will describe and analyze the Williams College Standards, Policies and Procedures for Digital Collections the using the framework presented in Xie and Matusiak's Discover Digital Libraries: Theory and Practice [@xieDiscoverDigitalLibraries2016b].</description></item><item><title>LS 566: Metadata Quality Problems</title><link>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/mqp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blackerby.github.io/portfolio/docs/outcomes/evaluate/mqp/</guid><description>William Blackerby
Dr. Steven MacCall
LS 566
25 September 2021
Assignment #2: Metadata quality problems
In their article &amp;ldquo;Achieving and Maintaining Metadata Quality: Toward a Sustainable Workflow for the IDEALS Institutional Repository,&amp;rdquo; Stein, Applegate, and Robbins give a useful overview of the kinds of metadata quality problems that can occur in collections before detailing how they developed a workflow to address metadata problems in the institutional repository they manage. Here I will summarize the kinds of problems they discuss.</description></item></channel></rss>